[柯克]舰长日志，星历5730.2
[Kirk] Captain's Log : Star date 5730.2.
阿里安纳斯星球至关重要
The planet Ariannus is vital
作为太空商业通道的中转站
as a transfer point on regular space commercial lanes.
它受到细菌入侵的攻击
It has been attacked by a bacterial invasion
不加以控制会威胁到上面的生命
which threatens to render it lifeless unless checked.
我们的使命是净化它
Our mission... to decontaminate it.
契科夫先生，估计我们到达阿里安纳斯的时间？
Mr. Chekov, an estimated time of arrival for Ariannus?
按照目前的速度，我们的预计到达时间是三小时四分钟，长官
At present speed, our E.T.A. is three hours, four minutes, sir.
乌乎拉上尉，通知行星卫生部
Lieutenant Uhura, advise the planet's ministry of health
我们将开始净化程序
that we'll begin decontamination procedures
锁定轨道后立即开始
immediately upon locking into orbit.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
斯科提，这会带来问题吗？
Scotty, will that present any problems?
不会，长官，净化槽正在部署
None, sir. All tanks are being positioned.
舰长，传感器现实前方有太空飞行器
Captain, sensors indicate a space vehicle ahead.
在可视范围内吗？
Is it within visual range?
正在进入可视范围
Coming into range now.
它的航线很不稳定
It's following a very erratic course.
把它放在屏幕上，放到最大
Put it on the screen, extreme magnification.
我认为那可能是一艘星际舰队的穿梭机
I think that may be a Starfleet shuttlecraft.
那就是，契科夫先生
That is exactly what it is, Mr. Chekov.
看起来像是从星际基地4偷来的那个
It looks like the one stolen from Star base 4.
乌乎拉上尉，尝试在命令频率2上与他们联系
Lieutenant Uhura, try to contact them on command frequency 2.
是的，舰长
Aye, Captain.
没有反应，长官
No response, sir.
尝试所有频率
Try all frequencies.
是的，长官，在所有频率上呼叫
Aye, sir. Hailing on all frequencies.
船上有一个生物，类人动物
There is one living creature aboard...humanoid.
他受伤或生病了
He is either injured or ill.
穿梭机显示内部空气泄漏
His craft shows internal atmospheric leakage.
该生物可能会窒息
The creature may be suffocating.
[柯克]苏鲁上尉，激活牵引光束
[Kirk] Lieutenant Sulu, activate tractor beams.
牵引光束已激活，捕获到了，长官
Tractor beams activated. We have it, sir.
准备把它带到机库甲板上
Prepare to bring it aboard.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
乌乎拉上尉，派一支警卫队前往压力门
Lieutenant Uhura, send a security team to the pressure doors.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
史波克先生，跟我来，斯科提
Mr. Spock, come with me. Scotty.
[广播]机库门已打开
[Loudspeaker] Hangar doors open and clearing
正在清理穿梭机入口
for entrance of shuttlecraft.
穿梭机接近机库甲板
Shuttlecraft approaching hangar deck.
[苏鲁]舰桥呼叫柯克舰长
[Sulu]Bridge to Captain Kirk.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
机库门已关闭，甲板正在加压
Hangar doors are closed, and deck is pressurizing.
收到
Acknowledged.
一开门我们就进去，听我的指挥
We'll enter as soon as the doors open, and we'll go on my command.
[按钮哔哔声]
[Button Beeps]
柯克：宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the star ship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: to explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
让那成为你们最后的战场
Let That Be Your Last Battlefield
医生，你确定这种肤色
You are certain, Doctor, that this pigmentation
是这个人的正常状况吗？
is the natural condition of this individual?
那是我记录的，史波克先生
That's what I've recorded, Mr. Spock.
我们知道有哪个星球
Do we have any knowledge of a planet
可能产生这样一个种族吗？
that could have produced such a race of beings?
不知道，舰长  - 老骨头，你怎么看？
Negative, Captain. - Bones, what do you make of it?
我无法给出具体解释
I can't give you any specific circumstance that will explain him.
从他身上看，我们至少知道
And judging by looking at him, we know at the very least
他是一个戏剧性冲突的结果
he is the result of a very dramatic conflict.
史波克？
Spock?
舰长，从孟德尔的基础规律
There is no theory, Captain, from the basic work of Mendel
到最近的核苷酸研究，没有理论能解释我们俘获的东西
to the most recent nucleotide studies, which would explain our captive.
所有颜色渐变，从黑色到棕色
All gradations of colour from black to brown,
到黄色到白色，在基因上都是可以预测的
to yellow to white are genetically predictable.
因此，我们必须得出结论，这个外星人
We must therefore conclude that this alien
是通常无法解释的稀有物种
is that often unaccountable rarity...
一种突变体，独一无二
a mutation, one of a kind.
是的，我同意，就是这样
Yes, I would agree. That's the case.
你的预后呢，医生？
Your prognosis, Doctor?
我不能给你，吉姆，我从来没有治疗过
Well, I can't give you one. I've never worked on anyone
他这样的人或东西
or anything like him.
然而，你却在给他灌满有毒的药水
Yet, you are pumping him full of your noxious potions
就好像他是人类一样
as if he were a human.
史波克先生，当有疑问时，要遵守规章手册
When in doubt, the book prevails, Mr. Spock!
我已经测试了，血就是血，哪怕是和你一样绿色的
I've run tests. Blood is blood, even when it's green like yours.
器官在那里
The organs are there.
它们在一定程度上被重新排列，还有一些我以前从未见过的
They're rearranged to a degree, plus a few I've never seen before.
现在我增加了他血液中的含氧量
Now, I've enriched the oxygen content of his blood
并注入强烈的兴奋剂
and pumped in a strong stimulant.
而且我必须说他的恢复能力似乎非常好
And I must say, his recuperative powers appear to be excellent.
如果你允许，我要做进一步的研究
With your permission, Captain, I shall do some further research
并在舰桥和你会合
and join you on the bridge.
他苏醒了，博士
He's coming around, Doctor.
很好
Well!
人事不省了一会儿，但你现在已经脱离了危险
Touch and go there for a minute, but you're out of danger now.
你在星舰企业号上
You're aboard the star ship Enterprise.
我听说过，它是星际舰队的？
I've heard of it. It's in the United Fleet of Planets?
联邦，你乘坐的穿梭机也是联邦的
Federation. So is the shuttlecraft that you were flying.
是吗？
It was?
你一般不知道你偷的是谁吗？
Don't you usually know whose property you've stolen?
我不是小偷
I am not a thief!
嗯，当然不是普通的小偷
Well, certainly no ordinary thief,
考虑到你…占用的东西
considering what it is you...appropriated.
你的指控太过分了
You're being very loose with your accusations
不知道事实就下结论
and drawing conclusions without any facts.
我知道的是你乘着一艘不属于你的船离开了
I do know you made off with a ship that didn't belong to you.
我没有偷
I do not make off with things.
我的需求给了我使用它的权利
My need gave me the right to use the ship.
记下这个词，先生，它的用途
Mark the word, sir... the use of it!
您可以在星际舰队指挥部尝试这些法律托词
You can try those technical evasions on Starfleet Command.
那是你将面临指控的地方
That's where you'll be facing your charges.
[叹气]我很感激你的救援
[Sighs] I'm grateful for your rescue.
别提了，我们很高兴抓住了你
Don't mention it. We're pleased to have caught you.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我叫洛凯
My name is Lokai.
继续
Go on.
来自谢隆星
From the planet Cheron.
那是在银河系的最南端
That's in the southernmost part of the galaxy,
在一个未知的象限
in an uncharted quarter.
你离家这么远干什么？
What are you doing so far from home?
你明白，当我们完成我们的任务后
You understand that when we complete our mission,
我们会带你去星际基地，在那里你将面临严重的指控
we'll take you to star base where you'll face a very serious charge.
指控不是问题，我会归还船的，只要我…
The charge is trifling. I would've returned the ship as soon as l...
什么？你打算做什么？
Had what? What were you going to do?
你们人类都是一样的呆板，首先是谴责然后攻击
You monotone humans are all alike. First you condemn and then attack!
我不会再回答任何问题了
I will answer no more questions.
不管我们怎么看他，舰长，他肯定不是普通的人
Well, however we view him, Captain, he's certainly no ordinary specimen.
嗯，洛凯，我不知道对你来说怎样是正常的
Well, Lokai, I don't know what's normal for you exactly,
但如果我有你的读数，那将是有史以来
but if I had your readings, I'd be the most incredible
最令人难以置信的身体样本
physical specimen of all time.
我们从未遇到过像你这样的人
We've never encountered a being like you.
我想更多地了解你和你的星球
I'd like to know more about you and your planet.
我很累
I'm very tired.
而且非常不坦率
And very evasive.
或者至少说不热情，既然，那么…
Or at least not fully responsive. Now, then...
我坚持，我非常疲倦
I insist, I'm extremely tired.
因为你的报复性盘问
Made so by your vindictive cross-examinations.
我将不再回答任何问题
I will answer no more questions.
乌乎拉上尉
Lieutenant Uhura.
[对讲机]我是乌乎拉上尉
[Intercom] Lieutenant Uhura here.
通知星际基地4我们已经找到了穿梭机
Notify Star base 4 that we've recovered its shuttlecraft,
它将与它的…使用者一起返回
and it will be returned along with its user
一旦我们完成了在阿里安纳斯的任务
as soon as we've completed our mission at Ariannus.
是的长官
Aye, sir.
老骨头，如果你认为突变理论适用
Bones, if you're satisfied that the mutation theory is applicable,
我会在我的报告中记录下来
I'll make a note of it in my report.
除非我们从他那里得到更多信息，否则就提交这个
Unless we get more information from him, it'll have to serve.
[对讲机哔哔声]
[Intercom Beeps]
我是柯克
Kirk here.
[契科夫]：舰长，与外星飞船接触，长官
[Chekov]: Captain, contact with alien ship, sir.
我马上到，通知史波克先生
I'll be right there. Notify Mr. Spock.
把飞船放在屏幕上，苏鲁先生
Put the ship on the viewing screen, Mr. Sulu.
柯克：放大
Magnification.
依然没有，契科夫先生
Still nothing, Mr. Chekov.
我确认了，长官，它在那里
I verify, sir, it's out there.
最大放大倍数
Maximum magnification.
我一无所获，史波克先生，你的回应？
I draw a blank, Mr. Spock. Your response?
没有，舰长
Negative, Captain.
无故障，长官，读数持续
No malfunction, sir. The reading persists.
怎么了？
What is it?
那里有一艘船，舰长
There is a vessel out there.
会不会是一艘罗慕伦飞船，使用了隐形装置？
Could it be a Romulan ship using their cloaking device?
不是，它不是罗慕伦船只
Negative. This would not be a Romulan vessel.
它的配置完全不同
It is totally alien in configuration.
动力未知，该船的小尺寸
Motive power unknown. Small size of the craft
表明是一艘快速侦察船，只有一名或两名船员
indicates a rapid scout vessel, one- or two-man crew.
舰长，我试过了所有的呼叫频率，没有，长官
Captain, I've tried all hailing frequencies. Negative, sir.
船上的武器？
Weaponry on the vessel?
没有可识别的
Nothing identifiable.
这艘船显然是为速度而不是战斗而建造的
The craft appears to be built for speed rather than combat.
外面的东西看不见
Something out there can't be seen.
怎么解释？
Explanation?
没有，完全难以捉摸
None. Completely elusive.
事实上，它是看不见的
In fact, it's invisible.
看不见的
Invisible.
故障？
Malfunction?
没有传感器故障，读数持续存在
There is no sensor failure. The readings persist.
它直奔我们而来
It's headed straight for us!
闪避动作
Evasive action.
它跟着我们移动，长官，我们正在推向极限
It shifts with us, sir. And we're pushing to the limit!
激活护盾，苏鲁先生
Deflector shields activated, Mr. Sulu.
自动模式，长官
Automatic, sir.
我们在碰撞航线上
We're on a collision course!
它失控了或是自杀任务
It's out of control or a suicide mission.
拉响碰撞警报，红色警报
Sound warning for collision. Red alert!
[警报声]
[Alarms Blaring]
准备迎接碰撞，准备！
Brace yourself for collision! Brace yourself!
读数，史波克先生？
Readout, Mr. Spock.
它只是…解体了
It just disintegrated.
真有趣
Fascinating.
现在怎么样了？
What is it now?
它现在不见了，舰长
It is gone now, Captain,
但它似乎放下了一个外星人
but it seems to have deposited an alien presence.
在哪里？
Where?
就在这里，舰长
[Man]Right here, Captain.
解释一下，史波克
Explain, Spock.
独一无二？
One of a kind?
[警报声持续]
[Alarm Continues Blaring]
我是贝尔  - 毫无疑问，属于谢隆星
I am Bele. - Of the planet Cheron no doubt?
原谅我不正式的到达
Forgive my unorthodox arrival.
你的旅行方式也很另类
Your mode of travel was also unorthodox.
解除红色警报
Secure from red alert.
你的飞船怎么了？
What happened to your vehicle?
它为我服务了很长时间，不幸的是
It served me long and durably. Unfortunately,
艰难追逐的劳损已经超过了它的极限
the strain of pursuit has exceeded its qualities.
我刚好能够完成这次旅行并及时下船
I was just able to complete this trip and disembark in time,
否则我会和它一起在太空中解体
or I would have disintegrated in space with it.
一种独特的工艺，可惜我们无法回收来研究
A most unique craft. Pity it couldn't be salvaged for our study.
是的，它被特殊材料包裹着
Yes. It was sheathed in special materials
使其隐形
that rendered it invisible.
是什么让你来找我们？
What brings you to us?
你带着宝贵的货物，洛凯
You bear precious cargo, Lokai.
他在这艘船上避难，我是来认领他的
He has taken refuge aboard this ship. I am here to claim him.
这艘船上的所有人员都服从我的指挥
All personnel aboard this vessel are subject to my command.
没人可以不通过正当程序认领其他人
No one claims anyone without due process.
抱歉，舰长，我越权了
My apologies, Captain. I overstepped my powers.
“认领”无疑是一个不幸的词
Claim is undoubtedly an unfortunate word.
你的授权是什么？哪儿来的授权？
What is your authorization? From what source?
我是政治叛徒委员会的首席官员
I am chief officer of the Commission on Political Traitors.
洛凯被判叛国罪，但逃脱了
Lokai was tried and convicted of treason, but had escaped.
请问我可以见他吗？
May I see him, please?
他在医务室
He's in Sick Bay.
记住，由于你在企业号上
Remember, since you're aboard the Enterprise,
你受其规定的约束
you're bound by its regulations.
请求你的允许，舰长
Hmm. With your permission, Captain.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
好吧，洛凯，很高兴再次见到你
Well, Lokai, it's a pleasure to see you again.
这一次，我相信
This time I'm sure our joining
我们的会面将更久
will be of a more permanent nature.
舰长，恭喜你
Captain, you are to be congratulated.
洛凯从未如此平静过
Never before has Lokai been rendered so...quiescent.
我不会回谢隆，回到屠杀压迫者的土地！
I will not return to Cheron, to a land of murdering oppressors!
我告诉过你要去哪里
I told you where you were going.
我让你的同胞在这里只是出于礼貌
I allowed your fellow countryman here simply as a courtesy.
你会看到这个杀手如何回报你
And you see how this killer repays you,
正如他回报他所有的恩人
as he repays all his benefactors.
恩人？他是个骗子
Benefactors? He's a liar!
他们袭击了我们的家园，将我们从家人身边夺走
He raided our homes, tore us from our families,
把我们赶在一起像牛一样，然后把我们卖为奴隶
herded us together like cattle and then sold us as slaves!
他们是野蛮人，舰长
They were savages, Captain.
我们用心对待他们，视他们为家人，我们教化他们
We took them into our hearts, our homes. We educated them.
是的，只教育如何服务优等种族
Yes! Just education enough to serve the master race.
你是我们爱的产物，你用谋杀来回报我们
You were the product of our love! And you repaid us with murder.
奴隶为什么要对奴隶主仁慈？
Why should a slave show mercy to the enslaver?
奴隶？
Slaves?
几千年前就变了，你重获自由了
That was changed thousands of years ago. You were freed.
自由了！
Freed?
我们可以自由地做人吗？
Were we free to be men?
自由地做丈夫和父亲？
Free to be husbands and fathers?
自由地以平等和有尊严的方式生活？
Free to live our lives in equality and dignity?
是的，前提是你知道如何使用自由
Yes, if you knew how to use your freedom.
你没有足够的自由去屠杀和烧毁所有已经建成的东西！
You weren't free enough to slaughter and to burn all the things that had been built!
我试图打破一亿人的枷锁
I tried to break the chains of 100 million people.
我唯一的罪行是我失败了，为此我认罪
My only crime is that I failed, to that I do plead guilty.
事情是有秩序的
There is an order in things.
他要求一天之内建立乌托邦
He asks for utopia in a day.
做不到
It can't be done.
不是一天，也不是你想的十万年
Not in a day. And not in ten times 10,000 years by your thinking.
对你来说，我们是一个令人讨厌的永远不完美的种族
To you, we are a breed who will never be ready.
灭绝我们是你们的乌托邦计划
Genocide for my people is the plan for your utopia.
你这个疯狂的、肮脏的、讨厌的堕落阴谋家
You're insane, you filthy little plotter of ruin!
你恶毒地颠覆了每一个善良的思想
You vicious subverter of every decent thought!
你要回来为你的罪行付出代价！
Oh, you're coming back to pay for your crimes!
我认识你和所有那些与你
I know you and all those with whom you're plotting
密谋永久夺权的人
to take power permanently.
当我回谢隆时，你就会明白什么是权力
When I return to Cheron, you will understand what power is.
我将拥有追随者的军队
I will have armies of followers.
先生们，现在很清楚你们彼此非常了解
It's now very clear you know each other extremely well, gentlemen.
这艘船唯一能提供的服务就是把你们聚在一起
The only service this ship can offer is to bring you together.
它不是战场
It is not a battlefield!
舰长，我领导的是革命者，不是罪犯
Captain, I led revolutionaries, not criminals!
我要求政治庇护，这艘船是庇护所
I demand political asylum. This ship is a sanctuary.
我再告诉你一次，对你来说，这艘船就是一座监狱
I'll tell you once more. For you, this ship is a prison.
舰长，你必须
Captain, it is imperative
将洛凯送回谢隆进行审判
that you return Lokai to Cheron for judgment.
专员，谢隆不属于联邦，没有签署任何条约
Commissioner, Cheron is not in the Federation. No treaties have been signed.
你对他的所有权的要求不能得到满足
Your demand for possession of this prisoner cannot be honored.
没有引渡程序允许这样做
There are no extradition procedures to allow it.
清楚了吗，贝尔专员？
Is that clear, Commissioner Bele?
队长，我希望你理智点
Captain, I hope you will be sensible.
你是什么意思？
How do you mean?
合作
Cooperation.
我不能偏袒任何一方
I cannot take sides.
既然我无船返回谢隆
Since I am without a vessel to return to Cheron,
我坚决要求你立刻带我们去那里
I insist that you take us there immediately.
不可能，我有任务要完成
Impossible. I have a mission to accomplish.
有一个星球需要净化，数以百万计的生命处于危险之中
There's a planet to be decontaminated. Millions of lives are at stake.
完成后，我将返回星际基地4
Once that has been completed, I'll return to Star base 4 and
并把你们俩交给当局，你可以向他们说明情况
and turn you both over to the authorities. You can make your case to them.
对不起，舰长
I am sorry, Captain.
那不令人满意，一点都不令人满意
That will not be satisfactory, not at all satisfactory.
专员，作为来自遥远星球的来访贵宾
Commissioner, as a visiting dignitary from a far planet,
我在这艘船上为你提供一切款待
I offer you every hospitality aboard this ship.
选择任何其他航线
Choose any other course ...
你是舰长
You're the captain.
是的，我是
Yes, I am.
我想我们可以认为你的问题…解决了
I think we can consider your...problem...settled.
至少就目前而言
At least for the present.
我已经在6号甲板上为你订了客房
I have ordered guest quarters for you on deck six.
我建议你好好休息
And I suggest you get a great deal of rest.
尤其是你的声带
Especially your vocal chords.
看来你会有双重机会
It seems you'll have a double opportunity
在星际基地4上实践你的演讲
to practice your oratory on Star base 4.
[对讲机]契科夫呼叫柯克舰长
[Intercom] Chekov to Captain Kirk.
契科夫呼叫柯克舰长，紧急
Chekov to Captain Kirk. Urgent.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
舰长，我们偏离航线了
Captain, we're off course.
那就回到正轨
Well, get back on course.
就是这个问题
That's just it, sir.
这艘船自己换了一个新航向
The ship's taken a new heading all by itself.
我马上来
I'll be right there.
你找到故障了吗？
Have you located the malfunction?
[苏鲁]没有，长官，飞船无响应，我们正在离开阿里安纳斯
[Sulu] No, sir. The ship is unresponsive. We're moving away from Ariannus.
解释，史波克先生
Explanation, Mr. Spock?
难以描述，舰长，我正在调查
Elusive, Captain. I am investigating.
我不明白，我就是无法控制
I can't understand it. I simply have no control.
柯克呼叫轮机部
Kirk to engineering.
我是斯科提
[Intercom]Scott here.
斯科提，我们突然偏离了航线，检查操纵控制
Scotty, we're off course. Check maneuvering controls.
好的，长官，稍等
Aye, sir. Hold.
舰长，没有显示故障
Captain, no malfunction indicated.
切换到辅助控制
Switch to auxiliary.
是的，长官，通话完毕
Aye, sir. Out.
轮机部呼叫舰桥
Engineer to bridge.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
已切换辅助控制，长官
On auxiliary, sir.
等待检查
Stand by for check.
斯科提，我们还是不在航线上
Scotty, we're still off course.
我马上上来
-I'll be right up.
契柯夫先生，速度？
Speed, Mr. Chekov.
我们在以曲速8移动
We're moving at warp 8.
新航线呢？
And new course?
403，标记7
403 mark 7.
直奔煤袋星云，如果不停的话
Straight for the Coal Sack if there is no letup.
乌乎拉上尉，将船置于红色警戒状态
Lieutenant Uhura, put the ship on red alert.
[警报声]
[Alarms Blaring]
全体船员，我是舰长，飞船处于红色警戒状态
All hands, this is the captain. The ship is on red alert.
重复，飞船处于红色警戒状态
Repeat, the ship is on red alert.
飞船的方向控制
There has been an unidentified malfunction
出现不明故障
in the ship's directional control.
重复，飞船偏离航线，失去控制
Repeat, the ship is off course and out of our control.
[警报声继续]
[Alarms Continue Blaring]
契科夫先生，我们的新航向？
Our new heading, Mr. Chekov?
403，标记7
403 mark 7.
史波克？
Spock?
确认，舰长
Confirmed, Captain.
等待航线，坐标现在表明我们正在制定航线到…
Holding pattern. Coordinates now indicate we are charting course to...
舰长，谢隆位于403，标记7和标记9之间
Captain, Cheron lies between 403 mark 7 and mark 9.
我们正在去谢隆的路上，舰长，这艘船现在在我的指挥下
We're on the way to Cheron. Captain, this ship is now under my direction.
你们的5万个地球年里
For 50,000 of your terrestrial years,
我一直在银河系中追寻洛凯
I have been pursuing Lokai through the galaxy.
我跋涉了这么远，这么久，不是为了现在放弃他
I have not travelled this far, this long, only to give him up.
这艘船由我的意志驱动
This ship goes where my will drives it.
舰长，我们现在是曲速10并且在加速
Captain, we are now at warp 10 and the speed is increasing!
舰长，现在航线清晰地直达谢隆
Captain, course is now clearly straight for Cheron
无视一切带我们去阿里安纳斯的企图
despite all efforts to direct us to Ariannus.
我不会回到谢隆，你必须保证我的庇护
I will not return to Cheron! You must guarantee me sanctuary.
他现在帮不了你，你迷失了，洛凯
He cannot help you now. You are lost, Lokai.
你正在走向审判，走向最终惩罚
You're on the way to judgment, to final punishment.
阻止他！
Stop him!
不是这次，你这邪恶的垃圾，不是这次
Not this time. You evil mound of filth. Not this time.
我的事业是正义的，你必须帮助我，你们所有人
My cause is just. You must help me. All of you must help me!
哦，老掉牙的哭喊：可怜，可怜我！
Oh, the old cry: Pity me! Pity me!
他所到之处，都有人帮助他逃脱
Everywhere he's gone, he's been helped to escape.
在每个星球上他都找到了为他流血
On every planet he's found fools who bleed for him
为受压迫者流泪的傻瓜
and shed tears for the oppressed one.
但在这艘船上，你无处可逃
But there is no escape for you on this ship.
这是你最后的庇护所
This is your last sanctuary.
杀了他，杀了他！
Kill him! Kill him!
你们是两个同类
You're two of a kind.
我们都要去谢隆
And we are both going to Cheron.
你不能改变这艘船的航向，就像你不能改变我
You cannot change the course any more than you can change me.
这艘船去我想去的地方！
This ship goes where I want it to go!
警卫，把他们都关禁闭
Security, put them both in the brig.
相位枪调到击晕模式，开火
Phasers on stun. Fire.
[相位枪声]
[Phasers Whistling]
你的相位枪对我们的防护罩无效
Your phasers are ineffective against our shields.
你帮不上忙，舰长
You are helpless, Captain.
我真是个傻瓜，期待你这样的人的帮助
What a fool I am, expecting help from someone like you!
这艘船要去阿里安纳斯
This ship is going to Ariannus.
不，这艘船要去谢隆
No, this ship is going to Cheron.
我不会让任何事干扰
I will let nothing interfere.
我们要去阿里安纳斯
We are going to Ariannus!
十亿人的生命使它成为我们唯一的选择
The lives of a billion people make no other choice possible.
你太愚蠢了，舰长，没有选择
You are being obtuse, Captain. I am permitting no choice.
我的意志现在控制着它，没有什么可以打破它
My will now controls this, and nothing can break it.
贝尔
Bele?
嗯？
Hmm?
我是这艘船的舰长
I am captain of this ship,
它要遵循我为它设定的航线
and it will follow whatever course I set for it,
否则我将下令摧毁它
or I will order its destruction.
你在虚张声势
You're bluffing.
我会毁掉它的
I will destroy it!
你不能摧毁这艘船，就像我不能改变肤色一样
You can no more destroy this ship than I can change colour.
乌乎拉上尉，把舰桥连接到主电脑
Lieutenant Uhura, tie in the bridge to the master computer.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
电脑，自毁程序，你准备好复制了吗？
Computer, destruct sequence. Are you ready to copy?
[电脑]工作中
[Computer] Working.
[电脑哔哔声]
[Computer Beeps]
准备验证自毁程序代码1
Prepare to verify destruct sequence code one.
[电脑哔哔声]
[Computer Beeps]
电脑，我是联邦星舰企业号的詹姆斯柯克舰长
Computer, this is Captain James Kirk of the U.S.S. Enterprise.
自毁程序1，代码1-1A
Destruct sequence one. Code one, 1-A.
[电脑哔哔声]语音和代码1-1A验证正确
[Computer Beeps] Voice and code one, 1-A verified and correct.
程序1完成
Sequence one complete.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
我是史波克指挥官，科学官
This is Commander Spock, science officer.
自毁程序2，代码1-1A-2B
Destruct sequence number two. Code one, 1-A, 2-B.
[电脑哔哔声]语音和代码验证正确
[Computer Beeps] Voice and code verified and correct.
程序2完成
Sequence two complete.
斯科特先生
Mr. Scott.
我是斯科特少校
This is Lieutenant Commander Scott,
联邦星舰企业号的轮机长
chief engineering officer of the U.S.S. Enterprise.
自毁程序3
Destruct sequence number three.
代码1B-2B-3
Code 1-B, 2-B, 3.
[电脑哔哔声]语音和代码1B-2B-3
[Computer Beeps] Voice and code 1-B, 2-B, 3
验证正确
verified and correct.
自毁程序完成并启动
Destruct sequence completed and engaged.
等待30秒倒计时的最终代码
Awaiting final code for 30-second countdown.
史波克先生，这艘船是否回到了按我的命令为其设定的航线上？
Mr. Spock, has the ship returned to the course set for it by my orders?
没有，我们仍然直接前往谢隆
Negative, Captain. We are still headed directly for Cheron.
[电脑]自毁程序启动
[Computer] Destruct sequence engaged.
等待30秒倒计时的最终代码
Awaiting final code for 30-second countdown.
电脑
Computer...
我是联邦星舰企业号的詹姆斯柯克舰长
this is Captain James Kirk of the U.S.S. Enterprise.
开始30秒倒计时
Begin 30-second countdown.
代码000
Code zero, zero, zero
自毁0
destruct zero.
[电脑处理中]
[Computer Processing]
[电脑哔哔声]30秒、
[Computer Beeping] Thirty seconds...
29、28、27…
29, 28, 27...
25秒…
Twenty-five seconds...
让我们看看你阻止电脑执行我的命令
Let's see you prevent the computer from fulfilling my commands.
[电脑哔哔声继续]
[Computer Continues Beeping]
20秒…
Twenty seconds...
最后五秒，宇宙中没有任何命令
From five to zero, no command in the universe
可以阻止电脑执行其自毁命令
can prevent the computer from fulfilling its destruct orders.
[电脑]15秒…
[Computer] Fifteen seconds...
你可以用你的意志把这艘船拖到谢隆
You can use your will to drag this ship to Cheron.
但我指挥电脑，我拥有最终指挥权
But I command the computer. Mine is the final command.
[电脑]十、九、八、七、六…
[Computer] Ten, nine, eight, seven, six...
我同意！
I agree!
电脑
Computer.
我是联邦星舰企业号的詹姆斯柯克舰长
This is Captain James Kirk of the U.S.S. Enterprise.
连续代码123
Code one, two, three continuity.
中止自毁命令，重复
Abort destruct order. Repeat...
连续代码123
code one, two, three continuity.
中止自毁命令
Abort destruct order.
[电脑哔哔声]自毁命令已中止
[Computer Beeping] Destruct order aborted.
自毁命令已中止
Destruct order aborted.
史波克先生，这艘船驶向阿里安纳斯吗？
Mr. Spock, is this ship headed for Ariannus?
不是，舰长，企业号正在一个环形航线中移动
Negative, Captain. The Enterprise is now moving in a circular course.
以曲速10，我们哪儿也去不了
And at warp 10, we're going now here mighty fast.
我警告过你他的背叛，杀了他！
I warned you of his treachery. Kill him!
我们正在等待你履行你的承诺，专员
We're waiting for you to fulfil your commitment, Commissioner.
我很高兴让你完成
Captain, I am happy to have you complete
你的阿里安纳斯的救援任务
your mission of mercy to the planet Ariannus.
干涉这种有价值的事业是愚蠢的
It was madness to interfere with such a worthwhile endeavour.
但如果你愿意，完成后
But, if you will, upon completion, please,
请把我和我的叛徒俘虏带到谢隆
take me and my traitorous captive to Cheron.
我没有为控制这艘船做任何交易，先生
I make no deals for control of this ship, sir.
航线现在在您的掌控之中
The ship's course is now in your control.
船的航线？
Ship's course?
企业号在前往阿里安纳斯的航线上，舰长
Enterprise is now on course to Ariannus, Captain.
速度，斯科提？
Speed, Scotty?
曲速6，平稳运行，长官
Warp 6 and smoothly operating, sir.
好的
Good.
乌乎拉上尉，解除红色警报
Lieutenant Uhura, cancel red alert.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
让我重申我的立场，先生们
Let me reaffirm my position, gentlemen.
鉴于你们的所作所为，我可以把你们关禁闭，但我不会这样做
I could put you in the brig for what you have done, but I won't do it
因为你们对银河系的这一部分不熟悉
because you are new to this part of the galaxy,
它由星际联邦管理
which is governed by the United Federation of Planets.
我们生活在和平中，充分行使个人权利
We live in peace with full exercise of individual rights.
诉诸暴​​力和武力的必要性早已过去
The need to resort to violence and force has long since passed,
在这艘船上不会被容忍
and it will not be tolerated aboard this ship.
你们可以在船上自由移动
You are free to move about the ship.
我希望你们能借此机会
I hope that you'll take the opportunity
更多地了解联邦
to know more about the Federation
通过它最好的代表，我的船员
through its best representatives, my crew.
但让我说清楚
But let me make it clear.
我无法容忍干涉这艘船功能的行为
I will stand for no interference with the function of this ship.
全体船员，回到正常工作
All hands, return to normal routine.
通话完毕
Captain out.
你讲得很好，舰长
You speak very well, Captain.
你的话承诺为所有人伸张正义
-Your words promise justice for all.
我们尽量，先生
We try, sir.
是，我已经学会了等待行动
Yes, well, I have learned to wait for actions.
阿里安纳斯之后，正义是什么？
After Ariannus, what is justice?
我会等着看它被分配
I shall wait to see it dispensed.
[门打开，关闭]
[Door Opening, Closing]
真有趣，两个不可改变的敌对类人生物
Fascinating. Two irrevocably hostile humanoids.
要我说是令人厌恶
Disgusting is what I call them.
这种描述在科学上并不准确
That description is not scientifically accurate.
史波克先生，“厌恶”这个词
Mr. Spock, the word disgusting
准确地描述了我对这两个人的感受
describes exactly what I feel about those two.
今天闹够了
That's enough for today.
那两个人开始影响你们了
Those two are beginning to affect you.
我从我的行为中知道
And I know from my actions
你们一定都认为我是个火山般鲁莽的人
you must all think me a volcanic hothead,
在危险中喷出熔岩
erupting lava from my nostrils at danger signals
这只是我的想象
that are only figments of my imagination.
但请相信我，我的朋友，没有一刻
But believe me, my friends, there can be no moment
我可以放松警惕，只要贝尔在场
when I can have my guard down where such as Bele is present.
那么会发生什么？我扮演疯子
So what happens? I act the madman
发泄他强加于我的愤怒
out of the anger and frustration he forces upon me,
从而证明他的观点，我是一个疯子
and there by prove his point that lam a madman.
没有人知道他在压力下会如何反应，洛凯
[Man]No one knows how he'll react under pressure, Lokai.
[契科夫]毕竟，我们只是人类
[Chekov] After all, we are only human.
[洛凯]哈，契科夫先生
[Lokai] Ah, Mr. Chekov,
这就是我没有能力提醒你和你的船长
therein lies my lack of ability to alert you and your captain
像贝尔这样的人的真正威胁
to the real threat of someone like Bele.
你来自地球，在你们的星球上没有迫害
You are from the planet Earth. There is no persecution on your planet.
你怎么能理解我的恐惧
How can you understand my fear,
我的忧虑，我的屈辱，我的苦难？
my apprehension, my degradation, my suffering?
[契科夫]地球上曾经有迫害
[Chekov] There was persecution on Earth once.
我记得在历史课上读到过它
I remember reading about it in my history class.
[苏鲁]是的，但它发生在20世纪
[Sulu] Yes, but it happened way back in the 20th century.
今天没有这种原始的思想
There's no such primitive thinking today.
你在历史上读到过它，我明白了
[Lokai] You have read about it in history, I see.
我怎么能让你的肉体知道
How can I make your flesh know how it feels
看着所有像你一样的人
to see all those who are like you,
被鄙视，被屠杀
and only because they are like you,
只因为他们和你一样，更糟糕的是
despised, slaughtered, and even worse,
被剥夺作为一个生物的权利，最基本的体面？
denied the simplest bit of decency that is a living being's right?
你知道被拖出家园
Do you know what it would be like to be dragged out of your hovel
卷入另一个星球的战争是什么感觉吗？
into a war on another planet?
一场为你的压迫者服务
A battle that will serve your oppressor
并给你和你的兄弟带来死亡的战斗？
and bring death to you and your brothers.
将它交到星际舰队指挥部手中
Putting the matter into the hands of your Starfleet Command
是正确的程序
is, of course, the proper procedure.
我们多久会收到他们的消息，舰长？
How long will it be before we hear from them, Captain?
我希望答案已经在路上了
I expect the answer is already on its way.
那让我们喝到他们对我们问题有明智解决方案吧
Well, then, let us drink to their wise solution to our problem.
我们喝
Let's do that.
专员，星际舰队指挥部
Commissioner, Starfleet Command
可能无法达成您预期的解决方案
may not arrive at the solution you anticipate.
还有洛凯挪用的
There is the matter of the shuttlecraft
穿梭机的事情
which Lokai appropriated.
对此的审讯
The interrogation of that matter
对于星际舰队来说可能是最重要的
may be of paramount importance to Starfleet.
先生们，我们正在讨论一个度的问题
Gentlemen, we are discussing a question of degree.
确实，窃取穿梭机和
Surely, stealing a shuttlecraft cannot be equated
谋杀数千人的严重程度不同
with the importance of murdering thousands of people.
我们不知道洛凯有这么做
We do not know that Lokai has done that.
我们一致同意洛凯是个罪犯
One thing we are agreed on is that Lokai is a criminal.
[柯克]不，专员
[Kirk]No, Commissioner.
是洛凯拿了穿梭机，对不起
The one thing we're agreed upon is that Lokai took a shuttlecraft. Excuse me.
[对讲机]乌乎拉呼叫柯克舰长
[Intercom] Uhura to Captain Kirk.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
我收到一条来自星际舰队的信息，长官
I have a communication from Starfleet Command, sir.
好的，读一下
Yes, read it.
“星际舰队指挥部
"Starfleet Command
向谢隆的贝尔专员致以问候
"extends greetings to Commissioner Bele of the planet Cheron.
将他与他声称的囚犯运送到他的星球的
"His urgent request to be transported to his planet
紧急要求已纳入考虑
"with the man he claims prisoner has been taken under consideration.
很遗憾我们不能满足这个要求
"It is with great regret that we cannot honour that request.
星际条约规定
"Intergalactic treaty clearly specifies
未经正当程序不得引渡
"that no being can be extradited without due process.
在这种情况下
"In view of the circumstances,
我们毫不怀疑，在星际基地的听证会之后
"we have no doubt that after a hearing at star base,
将允许贝尔专员保留他的囚犯
"Commissioner Bele will be permitted to retain his prisoner
并提供运送…”
and will be provided transportation..."
够了，谢谢你
That's enough. Thank you.
和往常一样，洛凯成功地获得了盟友
As always, Lokaihas managed to gain allies.
等一下，专员
Now, wait a minute, Commissioner...
即使他们不承认自己是这样的的
Even if they don't recognize themselves as being such.
是的，他会再次逃避，延迟，再逃避，在这个过程中
Yes, he will evade, delay, and escape again and in the process
让成千上万无辜的人互相扼杀
put thousands of innocent beings at each other's throats,
让他们为与他们无关的事业而杀人
getting them to kill and maim for a cause which they have no stake in,
但他会扭曲他们的思想
but which he will force them
从而迫使他们接受这一点
to violently espouse by twisting their minds
用他的谎言，可恶的指控
with his lies, his loathsome accusations
和卑鄙的威胁
and his foul threats.
专员，我可以向你保证我们的思想
I can assure you, Commissioner, that our minds will not be twisted,
既不会被洛凯，也不会被你扭曲
not by Lokai, nor by you.
对于头脑最简单的人来说
It is obvious to the most simpleminded
洛凯显然属于劣等人种
that Lokai is of an inferior breed.
专员，显而易见的视觉证据是
The obvious visual evidence, Commissioner,
他与你属于同一种族
is that he is of the same breed as yourself.
你瞎了吗，史波克指挥官？看着我
Are you blind, Commander Spock? Well, look at me.
看着我！
Look at me!
你一边是黑色，另一边是白色
You're black on one side and white on the other.
我右边是黑色的
I am black on the right side.
我没有看到显着差异
I fail to see the significant difference.
洛凯右边是白色的
Lokai is white on the right side.
他们种族右边都是白色的
All of his people are white on the right side.
专员，或许我的母星瓦肯的经历
Commissioner, perhaps the experience of my own planet Vulcan
能为你提供一些有价值的参考
may set an example of some value to you.
瓦肯曾面临的着
Vulcan was in danger of being destroyed
同样被摧毁的危险
by the same conditions and characteristics
原因和谢隆一样
which threaten to destroy Cheron.
我们曾经是和你们一样的人，情绪激动
We were once a people like yourselves, wildly emotional,
致力于非理性的对立观点
often committed to irrationally opposing points of view,
当然，导致了死亡和毁灭
leading, of course, to death and destruction.
只有逻辑学科才使我的星球免于灭绝
Only the discipline of logic saved my planet from extinction.
史波克指挥官，我很高兴瓦肯得救了
Commander Spock, I am delighted that Vulcan was saved.
但你不能指望洛凯和他这样的人
But you cannot expect Lokai and people like him
自律行事
to act with self-discipline
就像你期望行星停止绕太阳运行一样
any more than you can expect a planet to stop orbiting its sun.
让洛凯说出他的不满
Let Lokai state his grievances.
听他讲，听他说
Hear him, listen to him.
也许他能改变
Maybe he can change.
也许他想改变他的观念
Maybe he wants to change.
他们不会改变
They cannot change.
改变是一切存在的本质过程
Change is the essential process of all existence.
例如，谢隆的人曾经一定有过单色的
For instance, the people of Cheron must have once been mono-coloured.
你是说像你们俩一样？
You mean like both of you?
毫无疑问，在很久以前，一定有一段时间是这样
There must have been a time, long ago, no doubt, when that was true.
[对讲机哨声]
[Intercom Whistling]
对不起
Excuse me.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
[斯科特]我们正在环绕阿里安纳斯
[Scott] We're orbiting Ariannus.
很好，开始净化程序
Very good. Commence decontamination procedures when ready.
完成时通知我
Advise when complete.
马上好，长官，通话完毕
At once, sir. Scott out.
我听说在你们的星球上
I once heard that on some of your planets
人们相信他们是猿的后裔
people believe they are descended from apes.
实际的理论是所有生命形式
The actual theory is that ail life-forms evolved
都是从较低层次进化到更高级的阶段
from the lower levels to the more advanced stages.
准备净化程序
Ready for decontamination.
准备好了，长官
Ready, sir.
这里准备好了
Ready here.
准备好了，斯科特先生
Ready, Mr. Scott.
苏鲁先生，锁定阿里安纳斯请求的坐标
Mr. Sulu, lock into coordinates requested by Ariannus.
已锁定，长官
Locked in, sir.
契科夫先生，为喷雾部署净化槽
Mr. Chekov, position tanks for spray release.
净化槽已就位
Tanks positioned.
乌乎拉上尉，通知阿里安纳斯，任务根据信号开始
Lieutenant Uhura, advise Ariannus the mission is to begin on signal.
必须准备好所有地面预防措施
All ground precautions must be ready.
阿里安纳斯说“开始”
Ariannus says, "go ahead."
好吧，全速前进
Well, let 'er rip.
斯科特呼叫柯克舰长
Scott to Captain Kirk.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
首次运行完成，长官
First run complete, sir.
好的，重复程序以最大化效果
Good. Repeat procedure for maximum effect.
好的，长官
Aye, sir.
准备重复净化程序
Ready to repeat decontamination procedure.
准备好了，长官
Ready, sir.
苏鲁先生？
Mr. Sulu?
我准备好了
Ready here.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
我们正在完成最后一圈
We're completing the final orbit.
我正在等待设定航线的指示
I'm awaiting instructions to set course for the next destination.
很好，我们马上就来，设定去星际基地4的方向控制
Very good. We'll be right up. Set directional controls for Star base 4.
通话完毕
Kirk out.
你和我们一起去舰桥吗？
Will you join us on the bridge?
求之不得
There is nothing I would like more.
柯克：舰长日志，星历5730.7
Captain's Log : Star date 5730. 7.
我们完成了阿里安纳斯的任务
Having completed our mission to Ariannus,
企业号正飞往星际基地4
the Enterprise is now on course to Star base 4.
船员进行正常工作
The crew is on normal routine,
没有发生任何事故
and we are proceeding without incident.
有麻烦，契科夫先生？
Trouble, Mr. Chekov?
我不太清楚，史波克先生
I don't rightly know, Mr. Spock.
我试图按照命令规划前往星际基地4
I was trying to program for Star base 4 as ordered.
我无法得到回应
I can't get a response.
它似乎死机了，长官
It just seemed to go dead, sir.
舰长，一些电脑内存库被烧毁了
Captain, some of the memory banks of the computer are burned out.
你能确定哪些吗？
Can you determine which ones?
方向控制和自毁，舰长
The directional control and the self-destruct, Captain,
都烧坏了
are both burnt out.
我是这么干的
I did it like this.
[电气噼啪声]
[Electrical Crackling]
柯克：舰长日志，星号5730.6
Captain's Log : Star date 5730. 6.
在一次破坏行为中
In a deliberate act of sabotage,
贝尔专员烧毁了我们的自毁机制
Commissioner Bele has burned out our destruct mechanism
并且用意志再次接管了
and through the power of his will has again taken over
企业号的方向控制
directional control of the Enterprise.
现在我们可以别废话直接去谢隆吗？
Now can we go to Cheron without any more discussion?
目前，我似乎别无选择
At the moment, I seem to have no choice.
所以这就是阿里安纳斯之后的正义
So this is justice after Ariannus!
你签了我的死刑执行令，我警告过你会发生什么
You have signed my death warrant. I warned you what to expect.
你会继续让这种对正义的嘲弄继续下去吗？
Will you continue to let this mockery of justice go on?
如果你是正义的拥护者，请证明这一点！杀了他！
If you are partisans of justice, prove it! Kill him!
[契科夫]我们不是杀手
[Chekov] We are not killers.
你能做什么？只在嘴上伸张正义吗？
What do you do? Carry justice on your tongues?
你只会为它乞求，但你不会为它而战或死
You will beg for it, but you won't fight or die for it.
经过多年的领导战斗，你似乎很有活力
After so many years of leading the fight, you seem very much alive.
我怀疑他的许多追随者也能这样说
I doubt that the same can be said for many of his followers.
你完了，洛凯！
You're finished, Lokai!
我们已经把你的种族关在了谢隆上
We've got your kind penned in on Cheron into little districts.
那不会改变
It's not going to change.
你搜寻了整个银河系，一无所获，除了单色垃圾
You've combed the galaxy and come up with nothing but mono-coloured trash,
行善者和流血的心
do-gooders and bleeding hearts.
你死定了，你这个半白人
You're dead, you half-white!
你这个没用的无聊家伙
You useless pieces of bland flesh.
我要带你走，你个半黑！
I'll take you with me, you half-black.
贝尔，你再这样下去
Bele, you keep this up,
就永远无法和你的囚犯一起去谢隆了
and you'll never get to Cheron with your prisoner.
飞船的舰桥将受到不可挽回的损坏
The rest of this ship will be irreparably damaged.
这将是你们最后的战场
This will be your final battlefield.
你5万年的追寻都白费了
Your 50,000 years of pursuit will have been wasted.
而你，洛凯，将在太空中死去
And you, Lokai, you'll die here in space.
你不会激励更多的信徒，你的事业将结束
You'll inspire no more disciples. Your cause will be ended.
记住，舰长，政治庇护所是我的权利
Remember, Captain, political sanctuary is my right.
我是你的俘虏，尊重这一权利
I am your prisoner. Honour that right,
否则战斗会继续，你的船会被烧毁
or the fight will go on and your ship will burn up.
你说到点子上了
You've made your point.
如果你听他的诡计
If you listen to his legalistic trickery,
我将不得不摧毁这艘船
I shall have to destroy this ship and everybody aboard.
我明白了
I understand.
你会把企业号归还给我吗？
Will you return the Enterprise to my control?
为什么不？
Why not?
斯科提，方向控制维修是否已经完成？
Scotty, have repairs on directional control been completed?
是的，长官，已改道
Aye, sir, rerouted.
检查控制器和坐标
Check controls and coordinates.
[苏鲁]控制器操作中，企业号一如既往地作出响应
[Sulu] Controls operating. The Enterprise is responding.
舰长，真不错
Captain, it's beautiful.
锁定坐标
Locking onto coordinates.
舰长，我们在谢隆的扫描范围内
Captain, we are within scanning range of Cheron.
是否在可视范围内？
Is it within visual range?
现在进入范围内，舰长
Coming within visual range now, Captain.
契科夫，把它放在屏幕上，最大放大倍数
Chekov, put it on the screen, extreme magnification.
你扫描到了什么？
What are you picking up?
几个非常大的城市，无人居住
Several large cities, uninhabited.
巨大的交通系统，没有交通
Extensive traffic systems, barren of traffic.
低等动物和植物侵占城市
Lower animal sand vegetation encroaching on the cities.
根本没有智能生命形式显示，舰长
No sapient life-forms registering at all, Captain.
[史波克]没有自然灾害的证据
[Spock] There is no evidence of natural disaster,
然而，还有大量未掩埋的尸体
yet there are vast numbers of unburied corpses in all cities.
你的意思是…所有的人都死了？
You mean, all the people are dead?
都死了，舰长
All dead, Captain.
他们已经彻底消灭了对方
They have annihilated each other totally.
我的人民，都死了？
My people, my... all dead?
是的，专员，所有人
Yes, Commissioner, all of them.
没有一个活着？
No one alive?
完全没有，先生
None at all, sir.
是你们这帮凶手干的！
Your band of murderers did this.
是你们的种族灭绝狂做的！
Your insane asylum maniacs did this!
停下来！你们两个怎么了？
Stop it! What's the matter with you two?
你们没听到史波克说的吗？你的星球已经死了
Didn't you hear Spock? Your planet is dead!
因为仇恨谢隆上已经没有活人了
There's nobody alive on Cheron because of hate.
你为之奋斗的目标已不复存在
The cause you fought about no longer exists.
花点时间喘口气，放弃你们的仇恨
Give yourselves time to breathe. Give up your hate.
欢迎你们和我们一起生活
You're welcome to live with us.
听我说
Listen to me.
如果你们不停止仇恨
You both must end up dead
你们俩最后都会死
if you don't stop hating.
你是一个理想主义的梦想家
You're an idealistic dreamer.
贝尔
Bele?
追捕结束了
The chase is finished.
他逃不出我的手心
He must not escape me.
他能去哪里？
Where can he go?
贝尔？
Bele?
先生，我要通知警卫吗？
Shall I alert security, sir?
不，上尉
No, Lieutenant.
他们能跑到哪里去？
Where can they run?
[史波克]舰长，我用船上的传感器上找到了他们
[Spock] Captain, I have located them on ship's sensors.
贝尔在3号甲板上追逐洛凯
Bele is chasing Lokai on deck 3.
贝尔正在经过3号娱乐室
Bele is passing recreation room 3,
接近船员休息室
approaching the crewmen's lounge.
洛凯跑过船员休息室
Lokai is running past the crewmen's lounge.
洛凯刚刚抵达5号甲板
Lokai has just arrived on deck 5.
经过3号娱乐室.
Passing recreation room 3.
[传送装置嗡嗡声]
[Transporter Whirring]
[Transporter Humming]
舰长，有人激活了传送装置
Captain, someone has activated the transporter mechanism.
史波克，传送室里有人吗？
Spock, anyone in the transporter room?
没有，舰长，传送室是空的
Negative, Captain. Transporter room is clear.
然而，有一个生命形式正在星球上物质化
However, there is a life-form materializing on the planet.
是洛凯，他回到了谢隆
It is Lokai. He is back on Cheron.
那里没人会审判他，他的法官都死了
There's nobody there to try him. His judges are all dead.
舰长，传送装置再次被激活
Captain, the transporter mechanism has been activated again.
当然
Of course.
是贝尔，舰长
It is Bele, Captain.
[传送装置嗡嗡声]
[Transporter Whirring]
[Transporter Humming]
而另一个生命形式出现在谢隆上
And another life-form has appeared on Cheron.
这没有任何意义
It doesn't make any sense.
期望从这种极端观点的两种心态中获得理智
To expect sense from two mentalities of such extreme viewpoints
是不合逻辑的
is not logical.
但是他们的星球已经死了，谁是对的重要吗？
But their planet's dead. Does it matter now which one's right?
对洛凯和贝尔来说不是这样，对他们来说重要的是他们的仇恨
Not to Lokai and Bele. All that matters to them is their hate.
你认为这就是他们所拥有的一切吗？
Do you suppose that's all they ever had, sir?
不，但他们只剩下这些了
No. But that's all they have left.
曲速2，苏鲁先生，设定去星际基地4的航线
Warp factor 2, Mr. Sulu. Set course for Star base 4.